DAVID MUTIKAINEN

dmuti.90@gmail.com

C

705-971-8677

•

Sault Ste. Marie ON

SKILLS

- Quality Control Guidelines
- Data Entry
- Documentation
- · Mentoring and Teaching
- Excellent Verbal Communication
- Team Leadership
- System Troubleshooting
- MS Excel, Word, PPT
- SQL

EDUCATION

Algoma University
Sault Ste. Marie • 04/2018

Bachelor of Business AdministrationMarketing

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Resourceful Analyst with 6 years of industry experience. Manages diverse projects ranging from single files to large aggregates of data, to sort, prioritize and correct issues. Proven track record in coordinating tasks, ensuring accuracy in records and documentation and maintaining compliance with internal and external requirements. Possesses strong leadership and collaboration skills. Effective communicator with the ability to liaise with different teams and stakeholders, offering timely support and guidance.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

2018 Algoma University's President's Appreciation Award

• For outstanding contributions to student success and student life.

2021 EPL (Energy Profiles Limited) Community Award

 In recognition of team members who have had a profound, positive impact on the lives of others through their work, be they peers, clients, or otherwise.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Brightly Software - Data Integrity & Support Analyst Toronto • 07/2019 - 12/2023

- Managing a team of analysts utilizing OCR software and proprietary internal tools for data capture, data entry and data validation.
- Training and providing ongoing support to analysts for data entry using a proprietary internal tool.
- Member of a sub-team responsible for advanced utility accounting tasks, including: variance analysis of utility accounts, and loading energy market rates.
- Serve as the Client Contact for two large clients. Responsibilities include data entry, AP File preparation, ongoing communication with the client, contacting utility vendors to address utility billing issues, and communicating internally to support cross-team functionality.
- Member of an Emissions Reporting team with the primary responsibility of ensuring accurate data loading for a large client.
- All tasks previously mentioned include the utilization of MS Excel and SQL to prepare datasets for analysis, and to troubleshoot issues with data flow in the database.
- Interviewed qualified applicants for entry level positions.

Ontario Lottery And Gaming (OLG) - Payroll Compliance Analyst Sault Ste. Marie, ON • 04/2017 - 12/2018

- Responsible for processing data necessary to initiate and maintain accurate payment of wages, special payments and reimbursements, and general deductions.
- Analyzing multiple audits and conducting extensive validation to ensure adherence with controls, policies, collective agreements and government regulations.
- Prepared documentation and records for upcoming audits and inspections.

Algoma University - Teaching Assistant, Tutor Sault Ste. Marie, ON • 09/2016 - 04/2017

- Served as the TA for Business Statistics.
- Served as a tutor for multiple Business Administration courses, working in one-on-one and group settings.
- Helped with grading assignments and tests, providing constructive feedback to students based on results.
- Assisted in maintaining engaging and respectful educational environment by promoting discipline and cooperation.